<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sleep Deprivation on Ghostdogs</title>
    <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/tags/sleep-deprivation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sleep Deprivation on Ghostdogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 01:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ghostdogs.co.uk/tags/sleep-deprivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tam and Mammy</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/tam-and-mammy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 01:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/tam-and-mammy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few days things have changed. We had been out for a walk around the park and something clicked in Tam. Before we even got home he was asking about the photos on the memory wall. At home he points at the photo and I tell him the story of when the photo was taken. An hour or after we got home he sat down at the computer and asked &amp;ldquo;more photos&amp;rdquo;. He had a quiet 30 minutes or so looking at photos and sometimes asking me about the photos. Not all were his Mammy, but a lot were.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back (6 weeks holiday)</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/looking-back-6-weeks-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/looking-back-6-weeks-holiday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three more sleeps to go and Tam is back at school. Lots to do. With the biggest thing to achieve is to get Tam back in the routine of getting ready and going to school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grief Monster</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/grief-monster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 05:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/grief-monster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The grief monster is back again with Tam and his dreams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Good to Yourself</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/be-good-to-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 04:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/be-good-to-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I was told early on in this journey was to &amp;ldquo;be good to yourself&amp;rdquo;. I was told this by medical professional, social services, friends, Tams teachers. At the time I could not see how to do this and also what difference it would make. I really could not see how to be good to myself. I had no idea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half Term</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/half-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 06:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/half-term/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its 5am on Monday 4th November and half term is almost over. In a few hours the taxi will arrive to take Tam to school. Right now he is sitting quiet with his iPad paused watching Wildlife SOS. All is quiet, nice and quiet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5am</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/5am/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 05:21:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/5am/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its 5am and another night of Tam being petrified to sleep. He seems to be having terrible nightmares which lead to him screaming while he is asleep and wetting the bed. He is inconsolable when I wake him and sobs and will not allow me to hug him or even touch him. I will have that to deal with when he runs out of steam. Right now he is absolutely shattered and fighting sleep like a trooper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Far Have We Come?</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/how-far-have-me-come/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 13:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/how-far-have-me-come/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided I was going to review the month of September half way through and again at the end. I put this on my to-do list months ago and I have forgotten why. All I can think is that I did it for a reason so here goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
