<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Illness on Ghostdogs</title>
    <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/tags/illness/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Illness on Ghostdogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 22:57:56 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ghostdogs.co.uk/tags/illness/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>July 2020</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/july-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 22:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/july-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shitty long month - Tam been ill. Lots of bites. Difficult to move forward. Feel like I am in quicksand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back (6 weeks holiday)</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/looking-back-6-weeks-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/looking-back-6-weeks-holiday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three more sleeps to go and Tam is back at school. Lots to do. With the biggest thing to achieve is to get Tam back in the routine of getting ready and going to school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health (COVID-19 Edition)</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/health-covid-19-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 10:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/health-covid-19-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Keeping Tam fit and healthy has always been a major factor in looking after him. I have wrote about how not having the ability to communicate with him or understand the reactions he has to pain makes it difficult to decipher what is going on with him. For Petes sake he once ran into a bed end with such force and all he did was giggle. No crying, just giggling. He had a huge bruise and a big lump. Thankfully no break. The hours of confusion that day because my little lad was just giggling after banging his leg.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autism and Grief</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/autism-and-grief/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 14:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/autism-and-grief/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Kubler-Ross definition of the stages of grief are listed as Denial, Anger, Bargaining, Depression and Acceptance. I understand the principle behind these stages but they are very much a simplification of the grieving process. Everyone grieves differently and the cause of the grief also causes the grief to rotate in different directions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
