<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Worry on Ghostdogs</title>
    <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/tags/worry/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Worry on Ghostdogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 03:27:41 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ghostdogs.co.uk/tags/worry/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Worries</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/worries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 03:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/worries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 3:30 in the morning and Tam is busy on the computer recording himself reading into the computer. Once he is finished we play it back and read the book together with the recording playing. We then work on the word he does not read clearly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back (6 weeks holiday)</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/looking-back-6-weeks-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/looking-back-6-weeks-holiday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three more sleeps to go and Tam is back at school. Lots to do. With the biggest thing to achieve is to get Tam back in the routine of getting ready and going to school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health (COVID-19 Edition)</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/health-covid-19-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 10:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/health-covid-19-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Keeping Tam fit and healthy has always been a major factor in looking after him. I have wrote about how not having the ability to communicate with him or understand the reactions he has to pain makes it difficult to decipher what is going on with him. For Petes sake he once ran into a bed end with such force and all he did was giggle. No crying, just giggling. He had a huge bruise and a big lump. Thankfully no break. The hours of confusion that day because my little lad was just giggling after banging his leg.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failure with a capital F</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/failure-with-a-capital-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 11:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/failure-with-a-capital-f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today should have been Tams last day at school before the christmas break. It ended up not being that way.This morning he was spun up and running on empty after not getting much sleep. The time came to get ready and all hell broke loose. He got really upset and screaming. Asking for tight cuddles and asking &amp;lsquo;stay with daddy&amp;rsquo;. I pushed on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Stress</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/christmas-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 03:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/christmas-stress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its been a while since I have posted anything to the blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 01:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/reflection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways for me to learn is to reflect on my actions and look for progress in as many ways as I can. This process can be a bit rough as I am no where near perfect and if the truth be known I am a pretty faulty version of what is commonly known as the human race.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week End 15 Nov</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/week-end-15-nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 18:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/week-end-15-nov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past week has been a tough week in comparison to the previous week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Separation Anxiety</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/separation-anxiety/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 15:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/separation-anxiety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have spent quite a lot of time looking into any information that I can find on separation anxiety. Most of it is about the mental health aspect of it, some of it is about methods of coping with typical kids starting school or playgroups. Very little of it is about separation anxiety caused by grief. Either I am missing the point and it is inherent in the condition of grief and is taken as said or that not many people have looked at the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autism and Grief</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/autism-and-grief/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 14:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/autism-and-grief/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Kubler-Ross definition of the stages of grief are listed as Denial, Anger, Bargaining, Depression and Acceptance. I understand the principle behind these stages but they are very much a simplification of the grieving process. Everyone grieves differently and the cause of the grief also causes the grief to rotate in different directions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cinema Again</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/cinema-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 20:32:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/cinema-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night Tam asked &amp;ldquo;to go to the pictures to see Angry Birds 2&amp;rdquo;. Plain as day, best speech so far. So chuffed that we went online and checked what was on at the pictures. No luck. Angry Birds 2 starts 2nd August.&lt;br&gt;
As we were looking Tam pointed at Spiderman - Far from home. &amp;ldquo;Go to the pictures, Spiderman far from home&amp;rdquo;, again as clear as can be. Wow. Ok Tam we go to the pictures and see Spiderman.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the holidays begin</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/and-the-holidays-begin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/and-the-holidays-begin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is Tam&amp;rsquo;s last day at what I would call junior school. He moves up to senior school in September. It&amp;rsquo;s really the same school but a different site a few hundred metres away. It feels like a big change for him and me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
