<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Ghostdogs</title>
    <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Ghostdogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:01:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>World View</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/1-alittlepolitics/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Oct 2020 00:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/1-alittlepolitics/</guid>
      <description>A little politics I have tried not to watch the news of what is happening around world and for the best part have stayed away from the television news. However, I feel that the talk of fake news and conspiracy theories being bandied around are getting to the point where humanity is showing that we have no future. If such a large percentage (and by that I mean anything more than 0.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Complaint</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/1-complaintandcorrection/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2020 03:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/1-complaintandcorrection/</guid>
      <description>Complaint and correction I got an email from someone (I said I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t) that I was spending too much time complaining on the website and I should talk more about the solutions to Tam and my problems. After a bit of a conversation and a read back they are right. The posts are a bit &amp;ldquo;poor me&amp;rdquo;. I do stand by my reasoning to begin with. They are written from the point of view of a grieving Dad, a Dad that is also grieving for the loss his son has had and how they have added to his life challenges.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music for Healing</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/1-musicforhealing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 03:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/1-musicforhealing/</guid>
      <description>Music for Healing A while a go I read Neil Peart&amp;rsquo;s book Ghost Rider - travels on the healing road. In it he talked about his tiny little soul and the alter-egos that he had. He was grieving for his daughter and wife who died over a short period of time. In case you don&amp;rsquo;t know the name Neil Peart he was the drummer in a band called Rush. If I say &amp;ldquo;Tom Sawyer&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Spirit of Radio&amp;rdquo; you might know them songs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>October is here</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/1-octoberishere/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 03:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/1-octoberishere/</guid>
      <description>October is here It&amp;rsquo;s a week since Tams birthday and it has been a real tough week. Tam was sent home on his birthday from school. He was full of anxiety and was asking me to swap his birthday presents for mammy. Heartbreaking. The truth is I would give everything for him to have his mammy.
He came back from school all upset and got even more upset when I told him that he was not back at school for a while.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13 years ago</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/13yearsago/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 05:21:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/13yearsago/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At 3pm today 13 years ago the world welcomed Tam Samuel Greenwell. My beautiful son. Bev had to have an emergency C section as Tam had wiggled himself into nearly hanging himself on the umbilical cord. Kids!!!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Late onset speech</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/speech/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Sep 2020 05:21:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/speech/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the longest of times both me and Bev would ask the support staff at school and in the medical profession - &amp;ldquo;when will Tam speak?&amp;rdquo;. None of them would give an answer. Now I get why. Every child is different and every autistic child is even more different.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September 2020</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/september-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 08:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/september-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well it’s the 20th of September today and we have 2 birthdays out of the way (Bevs and mine) with Tams in 4 days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healing Photography</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 08:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/photography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bad-start&#34;&gt;Bad start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over my adult life I have pretty much had a camera all of the time. Canon, Nikon, Olympus, Sony all kinds of cameras. I have used them for my own personal interests and also for work. I have always enjoyed photography and having the wonderful time of watching Tam grow up and the love he had for his mammy was great subject matter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Missing Bev</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/missing-bev/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Sep 2020 08:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/missing-bev/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Happy Birthday Bev&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to School 2020</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/back-to-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Sep 2020 08:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/back-to-school/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Back to School&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School - Why?</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/heading-back-to-school/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 08:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/heading-back-to-school/</guid>
      <description>With everything going on in the world why are the kids going back to school?
Oh this all feels so wrong right now. Tam was hating school before the shutdown. He was kicking scratching and biting me on a night once he realised he was going to school the next day. He was fighting in the morning getting ready and this continued getting him into the taxi. He was coming home with ripped tshirts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>1st September</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/september1/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Sep 2020 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/september1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;September is here again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/life/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really want to write something meaningful. Something that speaks of life at the moment.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crappy Times</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/crappy-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/crappy-times/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shoulder injury, missing Bev more every day, worrying about Tam going back to school, tiredness are all adding up to a real crappy time. I feel so down and low.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smiling</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/smiling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2020 08:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/smiling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Living with a person with autism is full of extremes. Being the lone parent of your child with autism is even more full of extremes. At times the easiest thing to do is to surrender, hang out the white flag and run with them. Forget about all of the things that life used to be and just run with them. Operate in their version of the world for a bit, see if you can make sense of it. Sometimes I have been able to and sometimes it just remains a mystery.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>July 2020</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/july-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 22:57:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/july-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shitty long month - Tam been ill. Lots of bites. Difficult to move forward. Feel like I am in quicksand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tams Journey</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/tams-journey/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 06:18:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/tams-journey/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few pictures of Tam over the years&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Worries</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/worries/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2020 03:27:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/worries/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s 3:30 in the morning and Tam is busy on the computer recording himself reading into the computer. Once he is finished we play it back and read the book together with the recording playing. We then work on the word he does not read clearly.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Tam has changed</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/how-tam-has-changed/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jun 2020 20:57:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/how-tam-has-changed/</guid>
      <description>  2012 - Long haired boo
    2020 - Too cool for school
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tam Mantra</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/tam-mantra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 17:56:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/tam-mantra/</guid>
      <description>Thought I would upload this little file of me and Tam doing an abridged versions of Tams calming mantra. Enjoy
  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bad Days</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/bad-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 03:44:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/bad-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Looking after Tam and myself can be tough. Over the past few days it has been really tough. Yesterday Tam was sick. Nothing he had eaten that I can blame but he kept purging for hours and it became too much. I pleaded with him to go to bed and rest as I was not coping.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tam and Mammy</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/tam-and-mammy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 01:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/tam-and-mammy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few days things have changed. We had been out for a walk around the park and something clicked in Tam. Before we even got home he was asking about the photos on the memory wall. At home he points at the photo and I tell him the story of when the photo was taken. An hour or after we got home he sat down at the computer and asked &amp;ldquo;more photos&amp;rdquo;. He had a quiet 30 minutes or so looking at photos and sometimes asking me about the photos. Not all were his Mammy, but a lot were.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>April Ends</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/april-ends/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/april-ends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a tough month.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Looking Back (6 weeks holiday)</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/looking-back-6-weeks-holiday/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 May 2020 00:41:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/looking-back-6-weeks-holiday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Three more sleeps to go and Tam is back at school. Lots to do. With the biggest thing to achieve is to get Tam back in the routine of getting ready and going to school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 More Weeks</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/3-more-weeks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 Apr 2020 05:22:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/3-more-weeks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, we have 3 more weeks of lock down.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to write about?</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/what-to-write-about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 22:43:49 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/what-to-write-about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;May you live in interesting times&amp;rdquo; - A curse (proven not to be a chinese saying)&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nocturnal</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/nocturnal/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 05:31:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/nocturnal/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nocturnal life is common amongst geeks. I have stayed up until the early hours and then got up at 6am and headed off to work, with a couple of hours of sleep. As I have got older, I have become less and less able to do it. Now, as a single parent of Tam, I have had to learn how to do it again. &lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What day is it?</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/what-day-is-it/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 05:51:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/what-day-is-it/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The last few days have seen us doing homeschooling, building and rebuilding our fort, tidying, reorganising DVD&amp;rsquo;s, and finally going out shopping. It has been a time fraught with anxiety. It has been a peculiar time and will no doubt continue to be weird.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolate Day 4</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/isolate-day-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Mar 2020 21:55:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/isolate-day-4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;bean-bag-day&#34;&gt;Bean bag day.&lt;/h1&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolation day 3</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/isolation-day-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 22:31:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/isolation-day-3/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night was the best nights sleep for both me and Tam. Tam did not wake once. No crying, no bad dreams, just sleep. This morning he still has his cough, but again it is on and off. No temperature for now, just a lad who is glad to be home and lying on the sofa watching a cowboy movie. He loves the old movies.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolation 2.5</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/isolation-2-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 18:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/isolation-2-5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shopping list for anyone entering isolation/quarantine&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolation Day 2</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/isolation-day-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Mar 2020 12:41:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/isolation-day-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tam has been a sweaty boy during the night. Asking for ice cubes and drinking lots. Checked his temp and it appears &amp;ldquo;normal&amp;rdquo;. For the most part he is behaving like he has a cold, just this time it is lasting more than a day. Normally when he gets a cold he just wants to sleep it off and that lasts a day. This is turning out to be a little different. He still has a tickly cough but it comes and goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isolation</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/isolation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 22:39:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/isolation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday Tam was getting back to normal. This morning he woke with a cough. It was not the usual cough but enough of a cough to be a worry. It went on for a couple of hours and was joined with a couple of sneezes and some sniffling. Temperature was OK but with Tam temperature is never a good indicator. He seems to have a standard temperature of 36C.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crazy World</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/crazy-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Mar 2020 02:14:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/crazy-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its Sunday at 11pm and Tam has been asleep on and off all day. 30 minutes here and hour there. A couple of hours ago he threw up. Still not sure if it was stress or ill. I can normally tell by the smell but this time I think it was half and half. Let&amp;rsquo;s put it this way, I cannot send him to school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health (COVID-19 Edition)</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/health-covid-19-edition/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Mar 2020 10:31:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/health-covid-19-edition/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Keeping Tam fit and healthy has always been a major factor in looking after him. I have wrote about how not having the ability to communicate with him or understand the reactions he has to pain makes it difficult to decipher what is going on with him. For Petes sake he once ran into a bed end with such force and all he did was giggle. No crying, just giggling. He had a huge bruise and a big lump. Thankfully no break. The hours of confusion that day because my little lad was just giggling after banging his leg.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Calmer</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/calmer/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Mar 2020 07:19:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/calmer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well its Tuesday morning at 5am and things have been calmer tonight. No biting, kicking. Calm and simple tea, lots of cuddles and a beautiful thank you at the end. Then Tam asked to go to bed and dragged me off with him. I knew he had not slept much the night before and was more worried about him getting some sleep than having a broken night. So at 6pm he was asleep and stayed that way until midnight. Kinda what I expected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This school thing</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/this-school-thing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 19:39:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/this-school-thing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We started the week with a three day stay at respite. It went well. Tam ate and was settled more than previous visits.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What has worked?</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/what-has-worked/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 17:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/what-has-worked/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am going to start off by saying I am nothing special. I am a dad nothing more nothing less. My brain is analytical, it&amp;rsquo;s good at pattern matching and fire fighting. Give me a bad IT situation and I will find a way to get it back to a good situation. I know I have faults, some major faults and I work on them every day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2 steps forward...</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/2-steps-forward/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 03:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/2-steps-forward/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Half term is over, respite was a success and the first 2 days at school took place. First day went fine, first night was great. My little lad was full of fun and knackered. He slept well. Second morning went ok but had a lot of tears as I sent him off to school. All however changed tonight.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 days of respite</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/3-days-of-respite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 23:32:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/3-days-of-respite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s day 3 of Tam being in respite. One more sleep and he is home again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Grief Monster</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/grief-monster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 05:12:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/grief-monster/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The grief monster is back again with Tam and his dreams.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Be Good to Yourself</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/be-good-to-yourself/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2020 04:02:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/be-good-to-yourself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the things I was told early on in this journey was to &amp;ldquo;be good to yourself&amp;rdquo;. I was told this by medical professional, social services, friends, Tams teachers. At the time I could not see how to do this and also what difference it would make. I really could not see how to be good to myself. I had no idea.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half Term</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/half-term-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2020 15:01:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/half-term-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know if this is a thing, but whenever I have got myself to a break of more than a few days I always end up sick for the first few days. The last few days at work have been so hectic and then time off and illness. Always seemed to happen, the same thing used to happen to Bev. Not sure other people have the same thing. One thing I do know is Tam has the same reaction.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week 14th feb (Updated)</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/week-end-14th-feb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 07:29:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/week-end-14th-feb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;15th February is the anniversary of my Dad&amp;rsquo;s death. He is in my heart and mind constantly. Always looking for what he would say or do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mantra</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/mantra/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 07:09:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/mantra/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Something that has been really useful lately is our little mantras. I use one to get Tam&amp;rsquo;s attention if he is getting a bit disregulated. It goes like this:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Days Off</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/days-off/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2020 01:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/days-off/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wednesday morning and Tam was on the road to getting off to school and he started to vomit. My mind was whiring. Was he really this anxious. In the months after Bevs death I was having panic attacks where I vomitted, was Tam at the horrible point?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Boy is hurting</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/my-boy-is-hurting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 01:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/my-boy-is-hurting/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tonight my boy is hurting. He has spent most of the night crying.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>All the worry</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/all-the-worry/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 13:14:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/all-the-worry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As parents life is full of worry. It does not matter what kind of child you have its full of worry. The only thing different in being a parent of an autistic child is that you have to decipher each situation. The obvious answer is not always the answer.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Day Back</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/first-day-back/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2020 18:50:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/first-day-back/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its 5pm on Monday Tams first day back at school since the middle of last week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enigma Wrapped...</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/enigma-wrapped/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 14:40:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/enigma-wrapped/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tam like any child with autism that is non verbal (or minimally verbal) is difficult to read. I often describe as &amp;ldquo;an enigma wrapped in a mystery stuffed in an envelope and packed into a crate&amp;rdquo;. No matter how I can read some of Tams behaviours and find ways to comfort him there is always a time when every thing I think and every action I take does not work and misses the mark that Tam needs me to find. This is frustrating for both of us.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Week(end)</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/the-weekend/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Feb 2020 06:22:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/the-weekend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If anyone dares to tell me that Tams current anxiety and stress is not related to school I think I will end up in the mental hospital. What I am writing took place on Friday afternoon or Saturday. It&amp;rsquo;s currently 4:11am on Sunday morning and for once we are all calm and quiet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This week (CONT)</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/this-week-cont/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 03:31:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/this-week-cont/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s currently 2:35am and after Tam had been down for a while he woke up crying and asking about school. It has taken about an hour to calm him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>This week</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/this-week/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 22:10:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/this-week/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a load of posts that I have been working on that just need a bit more work. The problem is that Tam is creating a lot of work and worry at the moments. It&amp;rsquo;s only Tuesday night and this is what we have had so far.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sometimes</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/sometimes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jan 2020 09:35:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/sometimes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tam has come home from school. He looks tired and loaded with cold. He could not be bothered with going out to the shops or for something to eat and cried when I asked him. So pyjama night it is. Wednesday nights are always Starbucks nights, a carry over from when Bev would take him out to meet a friend in town.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Still Fragile</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/still-fragile/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2020 14:16:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/still-fragile/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I look back at the past few years and try to understand everything that I have lost. I have lost my Dad, my Mam to dementia and then to death, and my love and sole mate Bev so very suddenly. Taken too soon. I try to take in all of that loss and work out how to become less fragile and how to nurse my tiny little soul back to some form of semblance of order again.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss you more everyday</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/miss-you-more-everyday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/miss-you-more-everyday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2 Years have passed and you are missed more every day my love. Its 2 years since we touched and talked and those 2 years have been the hardest of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Post Giftmas</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/post-giftmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Dec 2019 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/post-giftmas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Box Day&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A totally meaningless day on the calendar now, and an attempt at a quite day that did not work. Tam was not in a great mood and everything has wound him up. I am tired and he is feeding off that.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giftmas</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/giftmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 10:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/giftmas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its giftmas day. No decorations no wishing a happy giftmas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failure with a capital F</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/failure-with-a-capital-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 11:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/failure-with-a-capital-f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today should have been Tams last day at school before the christmas break. It ended up not being that way.This morning he was spun up and running on empty after not getting much sleep. The time came to get ready and all hell broke loose. He got really upset and screaming. Asking for tight cuddles and asking &amp;lsquo;stay with daddy&amp;rsquo;. I pushed on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Stress</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/christmas-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 03:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/christmas-stress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its been a while since I have posted anything to the blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 01:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/reflection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways for me to learn is to reflect on my actions and look for progress in as many ways as I can. This process can be a bit rough as I am no where near perfect and if the truth be known I am a pretty faulty version of what is commonly known as the human race.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/sleep-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2019 13:42:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/sleep-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This weekend has been terrible for sleep. Tam has soldiered on with about 4 hours sleep total. It&amp;rsquo;s Sunday evening and I have been trying to talk to him about sleep and it has degraded into him attacking me. I have a bit mark on my hand and a cut on my nose. Everything I have done to calm him down has failed. I have him in bed with a red led strip under the bed and he is crying and tossing around. It breaks my heart. He has school tomorrow and the lack of sleep worries me as it can affect his behaviour.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week End 15 Nov</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/week-end-15-nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Nov 2019 18:16:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/week-end-15-nov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past week has been a tough week in comparison to the previous week.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Week ending 8th Nov</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/week-ending-8th-nov/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Nov 2019 19:23:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/week-ending-8th-nov/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The past week has been a good one. Starting Monday to Friday morning Tam slept exceptionally well for 3 out of the 4 nights. Down early and up early but solid uninterrupted sleep. It was absolutely brilliant. I felt rested, and he looked much more rested.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Half Term</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/half-term/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2019 06:09:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/half-term/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its 5am on Monday 4th November and half term is almost over. In a few hours the taxi will arrive to take Tam to school. Right now he is sitting quiet with his iPad paused watching Wildlife SOS. All is quiet, nice and quiet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Health</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/mental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 03:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/mental-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is probably going to be the hardest post to write from a personal point of view.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Answers</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/finding-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 01:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/finding-answers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wednesday and Thursday this past week Tam has shown some very difficult behaviour at school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Simple things need work</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/simple-things-need-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 14:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/simple-things-need-work/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is all very easy to take what seem like small things for granted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/change/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2019 18:08:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/change/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A change is as good as a rest, that&amp;rsquo;s a saying I have always appreciated in my life. Then life throws a change at you that you don&amp;rsquo;t want and it is anything but a rest. In fact it becomes the most heartbreaking, stressful and disturbing event of your life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pros &amp; Cons of Repsite</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/pros-cons-of-repsite/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Oct 2019 06:21:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/pros-cons-of-repsite/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the biggest steps I have taken with Tam is putting him into respite. So far it has been 1 or 2 nights in a lovely place that is especially for kids with autism. The staff are fantastic and do an excellent job of helping the kids to adjust to a new environment. I really could not ask for more from them.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Separation Anxiety</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/separation-anxiety/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 15:22:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/separation-anxiety/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have spent quite a lot of time looking into any information that I can find on separation anxiety. Most of it is about the mental health aspect of it, some of it is about methods of coping with typical kids starting school or playgroups. Very little of it is about separation anxiety caused by grief. Either I am missing the point and it is inherent in the condition of grief and is taken as said or that not many people have looked at the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blown Away</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/blown-away/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2019 13:34:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/blown-away/</guid>
      <description>Tam has just blown me away and made me cry in the best possible way. He walked up to me and signed to me and said out loud - &amp;ldquo;Tam Love Daddy&amp;rdquo; 14:30 Sunday 13th October 2019</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empathy</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/empathy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2019 09:42:05 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/empathy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;empathy /ˈɛmpəθi/&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;noun: empathy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the ability to understand and share the feelings of another.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep (I know its repetitive)</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/sleep-i-know-its-repetitive/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2019 23:12:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/sleep-i-know-its-repetitive/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On any day of the week when Tam comes in from school he follows a very prescribed path of tasks and objectives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tams Birthday</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/tams-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 19:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/tams-birthday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its Tams birthday.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>5am</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/5am/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2019 05:21:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/5am/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its 5am and another night of Tam being petrified to sleep. He seems to be having terrible nightmares which lead to him screaming while he is asleep and wetting the bed. He is inconsolable when I wake him and sobs and will not allow me to hug him or even touch him. I will have that to deal with when he runs out of steam. Right now he is absolutely shattered and fighting sleep like a trooper.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Far Have We Come?</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/how-far-have-me-come/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 13:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/how-far-have-me-come/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided I was going to review the month of September half way through and again at the end. I put this on my to-do list months ago and I have forgotten why. All I can think is that I did it for a reason so here goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthdays</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/birthdays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 09:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/birthdays/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;September is a month of birthdays. Bevs on 10th, Mine today 12th, and Tams on 24th. It used to be a fun month, now wrapped in grief.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Loving Memory</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/in-loving-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 10:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/in-loving-memory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is an angry day, tomorrow is a sad day. Grief knows how to really punch you in the gut around birthdays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taking a breath</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/taking-a-breath/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 16:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/taking-a-breath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tam went back to school today. He was real confused this morning. After thousands of times asking &amp;ldquo;going to school tomorrow&amp;rdquo; he was getting ready for school. It caused a little bit of panic as he had to get some things in place ready for him leaving. All weird stuff like his star projector has to be facing a certain way in his bedroom. He has to use his iPad and Kindle to watch particular things in the morning. He has to have his chair sideways when he gets his breakfast. All weird stuff but it makes him happy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School hols nearly done</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/school-hols-nearly-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 04:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/school-hols-nearly-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its the start of September and six weeks of holiday are nearly done. Only a few days left and a lot to do. Not least is to get Tam back into getting ready for school at the right time. That feels like an impossible tasks at the moment. Today is another day with no sleep. First of September and its 5am. No sleep. I have tried melatonin but he just got upset. I tried to keep him in bed but that became a fight. Right now he is wired, running around and aggravated. I am knackered and wondering when he will sleep. The only upside is that he is safe and fed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/september/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Aug 2019 23:20:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/september/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;September used to be a busy month, now its full of memories.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/sleep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Aug 2019 06:21:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/sleep/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tam has had a few weeks of fairly decent sleep patterns. 2-6 hours of sleep. It&amp;rsquo;s funny what becomes decent.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Form Filling</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/form-filling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Aug 2019 23:24:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/form-filling/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have spent the past month trying to fill in the Disability Living Allowance (DLA) form for Tam. It is a horrendous form. Today I managed to finish it. I can hear you ask why did it take so long. Well it a little window into looking after an autistic, anxious, grieving boy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter to the ones I have lost</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/letter-to-the-ones-i-have-lost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 06:34:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/letter-to-the-ones-i-have-lost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote this ages ago and posted it on a forum about sharing grief. May as well include it here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking is good listening better</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/talking-is-good-listening-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 15:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/talking-is-good-listening-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past week I have had the opportunity to speak with some parents of children with varying special needs. The parents varied from a single parent like myself to normal families with help from siblings or the wider family. I used the opportunity to listen and also to share a little bit. It is all too easy to sound like a victim when talking about the situation that you find yourself in. I am especially aware that even writing this that I can come across as playing the victim. It is my hope that people realise that I am not trying to play the victim and that I am just talking about the situation that I find myself in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autism and Grief</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/autism-and-grief/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 14:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/autism-and-grief/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Kubler-Ross definition of the stages of grief are listed as Denial, Anger, Bargaining, Depression and Acceptance. I understand the principle behind these stages but they are very much a simplification of the grieving process. Everyone grieves differently and the cause of the grief also causes the grief to rotate in different directions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Holidays and Autism</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/holidays-and-autism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Aug 2019 14:40:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/holidays-and-autism/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was not one of those kids that hated school, For me school was boring and the teachers struggled to keep me interested. Tam however loves school. It gives him the structure and engagement that he needs. Now matter how hard I try it is difficult to keep up the level of engagement that school gives him.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sleep Deprivation</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/sleep-deprivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jul 2019 15:10:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/sleep-deprivation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past two couple of years I have kept a log of Tams sleeping patterns. It is part of a larger journal that I write in everyday. I write the challenges, the wins, what&amp;rsquo;s worrying me and lots of other things. The contents of the journal is not something that I would be willing to share as a whole but one section of it has been very useful.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The hardest haircut</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/the-hardest-haircut/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2019 17:11:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/the-hardest-haircut/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As all parents of autistic kids know getting a haircut for their child can be a nightmare. The smells and noises of a barber or hairdresser shop can be overwhelming. It is not a good experience for anyone involved unless you find a smart, compassionate and patient soul to help with the situation. We did and this is the story.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cinema Again</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/cinema-again/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jul 2019 20:32:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/cinema-again/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Last night Tam asked &amp;ldquo;to go to the pictures to see Angry Birds 2&amp;rdquo;. Plain as day, best speech so far. So chuffed that we went online and checked what was on at the pictures. No luck. Angry Birds 2 starts 2nd August.&lt;br&gt;
As we were looking Tam pointed at Spiderman - Far from home. &amp;ldquo;Go to the pictures, Spiderman far from home&amp;rdquo;, again as clear as can be. Wow. Ok Tam we go to the pictures and see Spiderman.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Panic Attacks</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/panic-attacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2019 19:25:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/panic-attacks/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have had a couple of days to reflect on the past week and what me and Tam are doing. It has taken a couple of days because of panic attacks that I have had with some of the stuff me and Tam need to do.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You win or you learn</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/you-win-or-you-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 13:35:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/you-win-or-you-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now just to get things straight I am not talking about a competetion in what follows. I am talking about supporting my son and part of that is understanding his complex behaviour and seeing things from his point of view.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the holidays begin</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/and-the-holidays-begin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/and-the-holidays-begin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is Tam&amp;rsquo;s last day at what I would call junior school. He moves up to senior school in September. It&amp;rsquo;s really the same school but a different site a few hundred metres away. It feels like a big change for him and me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respite Part 2</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/respite-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 13:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/respite-part-2/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dropping Tam off at the respite centre was hard, especially after being at the beach with him all day. The drop off was quick and consisted of a kiss and a bye-bye. I hoped that all of the preparation had worked. I have talked to Tam many times about him staying at the centre and having an adventure and sleep over. With his lack of verbal comebacks it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to totally understand how much he understands. One part of me is that he understands almost everything, then there is the doubt and I think he is being thrown into things with no understanding and just terror and anxiety of what the hell is Dad doing, where has he gone. I wish I knew.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotional Day</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/emotional-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 01:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/emotional-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Written 16th July 23:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today has been an emotional day. It is just before midnight and for the first time since Bev died Tam is not with me. He is at a respite centre a few miles away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toys</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/toys/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 20:39:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/toys/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tam is at times very difficult to engage. His favourite things are tickles and rough and tumble. After that its his iPad and TV remote. By TV remote I mean that Tam has ultimate control of the TV with the ability to change channel and fast forward and rewind.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cinema Visit</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/cinema-visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 19:51:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/cinema-visit/</guid>
      <description>Today we went to the cinema. We went to a relaxed viewing which means the sound is turned down and the lights are set low. The expectation is that all kinds of kids will be there and pretty much any behaviour is to be expected. It did however hit me that the neuro-typical kids made more noise and caused more disruption. Go figure.
Check out - https://www.tynesidecinema.co.uk/film-and-events/special-screenings/access-cinema </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respite Part 1</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/respite-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 21:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/respite-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today me and Tam were separated for longest time. We spent 6 hours apart on a weekend. Yes, we are separate when Tam goes to school. This was only the second time in the last 18 months that we have been separate, but the last time I was in the same building. Today Tam went to a respite centre with me and I left him there. He went off to the beach and I went home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saying thank you is important</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/saying-thank-you-is-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 14:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/saying-thank-you-is-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the time since Bev died a particular kind of music and a particular band have given both me and Tam a lot of solice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory Box and Memory Wall</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/memory-box-and-memory-wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 12:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/memory-box-and-memory-wall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An idea was given to me early on to put together a memory box of things for Tam to use when he is thinking of Mammy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Average Tough Day</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/an-average-tough-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/an-average-tough-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Written 3rd July 2019&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silent Illness</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/silent-illness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 12:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/silent-illness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Any parent knows that when their child is ill that it is the most worrying of times. When a child is a bit quiet and complains of a belly ache any normal parent thinks a couple of polar opposite things at the same time. &amp;ldquo;I told you to stop eating so many strawberries&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;its appendicitis, and it about to burst&amp;rdquo;, both of these are normal reactions and you talk to your child to help make the decision as to what it is and before you get a chance to work it out they left off a large fart and are off playing again. It&amp;rsquo;s normal. Absolutely normal. When that does not happen and you end up in A&amp;amp;E at 2 in the morning well that&amp;rsquo;s a different story all together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>No miracle cures</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/no-miracle-cures/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jul 2019 22:44:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/no-miracle-cures/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a subject I was going to stay away from but I have had loads of emails, mostly from America on the subject of autism &amp;lsquo;cures&amp;rsquo; and how to make Tam well again. I have to say I was surprised and was not expecting the number of emails but the content has been sickening. I would have much preferred spam about anything else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 20:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/introduction/</guid>
      <description>I am not totally sure of my reasons for writing a blog or a book at the moment. All I know is that the main subject that I have been writing about, my son, his autism and grief are important to me. I have looked for research and guidance on the web and elsewhere and have found little of substance. There might be on Facebook and maybe stuff is hidden on there, but I am not on Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rich Content</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/rich-content/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/rich-content/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hugo ships with several &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/content-management/shortcodes/#use-hugo-s-built-in-shortcodes&#34;&gt;Built-in Shortcodes&lt;/a&gt; for rich content, along with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/about/hugo-and-gdpr/&#34;&gt;Privacy Config&lt;/a&gt; and a set of Simple Shortcodes that enable static and no-JS versions of various social media embeds.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
