<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Grief on Ghostdogs</title>
    <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/tags/grief/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Grief on Ghostdogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 03:17:24 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ghostdogs.co.uk/tags/grief/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Music for Healing</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/1-musicforhealing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 03:17:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/1-musicforhealing/</guid>
      <description>Music for Healing A while a go I read Neil Peart&amp;rsquo;s book Ghost Rider - travels on the healing road. In it he talked about his tiny little soul and the alter-egos that he had. He was grieving for his daughter and wife who died over a short period of time. In case you don&amp;rsquo;t know the name Neil Peart he was the drummer in a band called Rush. If I say &amp;ldquo;Tom Sawyer&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;Spirit of Radio&amp;rdquo; you might know them songs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>13 years ago</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/13yearsago/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Sep 2020 05:21:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/13yearsago/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At 3pm today 13 years ago the world welcomed Tam Samuel Greenwell. My beautiful son. Bev had to have an emergency C section as Tam had wiggled himself into nearly hanging himself on the umbilical cord. Kids!!!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>September 2020</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/september-2020/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Sep 2020 08:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/september-2020/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Well it’s the 20th of September today and we have 2 birthdays out of the way (Bevs and mine) with Tams in 4 days.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Healing Photography</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/photography/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Sep 2020 08:39:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/photography/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bad-start&#34;&gt;Bad start&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over my adult life I have pretty much had a camera all of the time. Canon, Nikon, Olympus, Sony all kinds of cameras. I have used them for my own personal interests and also for work. I have always enjoyed photography and having the wonderful time of watching Tam grow up and the love he had for his mammy was great subject matter.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What has worked?</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/what-has-worked/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 17:55:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/what-has-worked/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am going to start off by saying I am nothing special. I am a dad nothing more nothing less. My brain is analytical, it&amp;rsquo;s good at pattern matching and fire fighting. Give me a bad IT situation and I will find a way to get it back to a good situation. I know I have faults, some major faults and I work on them every day.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Miss you more everyday</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/miss-you-more-everyday/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2019 06:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/miss-you-more-everyday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2 Years have passed and you are missed more every day my love. Its 2 years since we touched and talked and those 2 years have been the hardest of our lives.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Giftmas</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/giftmas/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Dec 2019 10:26:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/giftmas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its giftmas day. No decorations no wishing a happy giftmas.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Failure with a capital F</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/failure-with-a-capital-f/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 11:27:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/failure-with-a-capital-f/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today should have been Tams last day at school before the christmas break. It ended up not being that way.This morning he was spun up and running on empty after not getting much sleep. The time came to get ready and all hell broke loose. He got really upset and screaming. Asking for tight cuddles and asking &amp;lsquo;stay with daddy&amp;rsquo;. I pushed on.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Christmas Stress</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/christmas-stress/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Dec 2019 03:14:54 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/christmas-stress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its been a while since I have posted anything to the blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reflection</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/reflection/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 01:43:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/reflection/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the best ways for me to learn is to reflect on my actions and look for progress in as many ways as I can. This process can be a bit rough as I am no where near perfect and if the truth be known I am a pretty faulty version of what is commonly known as the human race.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Health</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/mental-health/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 03:48:11 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/mental-health/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is probably going to be the hardest post to write from a personal point of view.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Finding Answers</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/finding-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2019 01:52:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/finding-answers/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Wednesday and Thursday this past week Tam has shown some very difficult behaviour at school.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tams Birthday</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/tams-birthday/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2019 19:23:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/tams-birthday/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its Tams birthday.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Far Have We Come?</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/how-far-have-me-come/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 13:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/how-far-have-me-come/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided I was going to review the month of September half way through and again at the end. I put this on my to-do list months ago and I have forgotten why. All I can think is that I did it for a reason so here goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Birthdays</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/birthdays/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Sep 2019 09:59:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/birthdays/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;September is a month of birthdays. Bevs on 10th, Mine today 12th, and Tams on 24th. It used to be a fun month, now wrapped in grief.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In Loving Memory</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/in-loving-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2019 10:22:37 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/in-loving-memory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today is an angry day, tomorrow is a sad day. Grief knows how to really punch you in the gut around birthdays.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter to the ones I have lost</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/letter-to-the-ones-i-have-lost/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2019 06:34:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/letter-to-the-ones-i-have-lost/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wrote this ages ago and posted it on a forum about sharing grief. May as well include it here.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Autism and Grief</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/autism-and-grief/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Aug 2019 14:34:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/autism-and-grief/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Kubler-Ross definition of the stages of grief are listed as Denial, Anger, Bargaining, Depression and Acceptance. I understand the principle behind these stages but they are very much a simplification of the grieving process. Everyone grieves differently and the cause of the grief also causes the grief to rotate in different directions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>You win or you learn</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/you-win-or-you-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 13:35:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/you-win-or-you-learn/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now just to get things straight I am not talking about a competetion in what follows. I am talking about supporting my son and part of that is understanding his complex behaviour and seeing things from his point of view.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotional Day</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/emotional-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 01:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/emotional-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Written 16th July 23:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today has been an emotional day. It is just before midnight and for the first time since Bev died Tam is not with me. He is at a respite centre a few miles away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respite Part 1</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/respite-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jul 2019 21:08:25 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/respite-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today me and Tam were separated for longest time. We spent 6 hours apart on a weekend. Yes, we are separate when Tam goes to school. This was only the second time in the last 18 months that we have been separate, but the last time I was in the same building. Today Tam went to a respite centre with me and I left him there. He went off to the beach and I went home.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saying thank you is important</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/saying-thank-you-is-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 14:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/saying-thank-you-is-important/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;During the time since Bev died a particular kind of music and a particular band have given both me and Tam a lot of solice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory Box and Memory Wall</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/memory-box-and-memory-wall/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 12:18:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/memory-box-and-memory-wall/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An idea was given to me early on to put together a memory box of things for Tam to use when he is thinking of Mammy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Silent Illness</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/silent-illness/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 12:53:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/silent-illness/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Any parent knows that when their child is ill that it is the most worrying of times. When a child is a bit quiet and complains of a belly ache any normal parent thinks a couple of polar opposite things at the same time. &amp;ldquo;I told you to stop eating so many strawberries&amp;rdquo; to &amp;ldquo;its appendicitis, and it about to burst&amp;rdquo;, both of these are normal reactions and you talk to your child to help make the decision as to what it is and before you get a chance to work it out they left off a large fart and are off playing again. It&amp;rsquo;s normal. Absolutely normal. When that does not happen and you end up in A&amp;amp;E at 2 in the morning well that&amp;rsquo;s a different story all together.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/introduction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 20:41:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/introduction/</guid>
      <description>I am not totally sure of my reasons for writing a blog or a book at the moment. All I know is that the main subject that I have been writing about, my son, his autism and grief are important to me. I have looked for research and guidance on the web and elsewhere and have found little of substance. There might be on Facebook and maybe stuff is hidden on there, but I am not on Facebook.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
