<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Holidays on Ghostdogs</title>
    <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/tags/holidays/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Holidays on Ghostdogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 16:30:03 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ghostdogs.co.uk/tags/holidays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Taking a breath</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/taking-a-breath/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2019 16:30:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/taking-a-breath/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tam went back to school today. He was real confused this morning. After thousands of times asking &amp;ldquo;going to school tomorrow&amp;rdquo; he was getting ready for school. It caused a little bit of panic as he had to get some things in place ready for him leaving. All weird stuff like his star projector has to be facing a certain way in his bedroom. He has to use his iPad and Kindle to watch particular things in the morning. He has to have his chair sideways when he gets his breakfast. All weird stuff but it makes him happy.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>School hols nearly done</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/school-hols-nearly-done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 04:52:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/school-hols-nearly-done/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Its the start of September and six weeks of holiday are nearly done. Only a few days left and a lot to do. Not least is to get Tam back into getting ready for school at the right time. That feels like an impossible tasks at the moment. Today is another day with no sleep. First of September and its 5am. No sleep. I have tried melatonin but he just got upset. I tried to keep him in bed but that became a fight. Right now he is wired, running around and aggravated. I am knackered and wondering when he will sleep. The only upside is that he is safe and fed.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the holidays begin</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/and-the-holidays-begin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/and-the-holidays-begin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is Tam&amp;rsquo;s last day at what I would call junior school. He moves up to senior school in September. It&amp;rsquo;s really the same school but a different site a few hundred metres away. It feels like a big change for him and me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
