<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Respite Care on Ghostdogs</title>
    <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/tags/respite-care/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Respite Care on Ghostdogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 01:50:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://ghostdogs.co.uk/tags/respite-care/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tam and Mammy</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/tam-and-mammy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 May 2020 01:50:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/tam-and-mammy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few days things have changed. We had been out for a walk around the park and something clicked in Tam. Before we even got home he was asking about the photos on the memory wall. At home he points at the photo and I tell him the story of when the photo was taken. An hour or after we got home he sat down at the computer and asked &amp;ldquo;more photos&amp;rdquo;. He had a quiet 30 minutes or so looking at photos and sometimes asking me about the photos. Not all were his Mammy, but a lot were.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Far Have We Come?</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/how-far-have-me-come/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2019 13:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/how-far-have-me-come/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I decided I was going to review the month of September half way through and again at the end. I put this on my to-do list months ago and I have forgotten why. All I can think is that I did it for a reason so here goes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Talking is good listening better</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/talking-is-good-listening-better/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2019 15:27:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/talking-is-good-listening-better/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past week I have had the opportunity to speak with some parents of children with varying special needs. The parents varied from a single parent like myself to normal families with help from siblings or the wider family. I used the opportunity to listen and also to share a little bit. It is all too easy to sound like a victim when talking about the situation that you find yourself in. I am especially aware that even writing this that I can come across as playing the victim. It is my hope that people realise that I am not trying to play the victim and that I am just talking about the situation that I find myself in.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>And the holidays begin</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/and-the-holidays-begin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Jul 2019 15:25:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/and-the-holidays-begin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Tomorrow is Tam&amp;rsquo;s last day at what I would call junior school. He moves up to senior school in September. It&amp;rsquo;s really the same school but a different site a few hundred metres away. It feels like a big change for him and me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emotional Day</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/emotional-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jul 2019 01:06:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/emotional-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Written 16th July 23:00&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today has been an emotional day. It is just before midnight and for the first time since Bev died Tam is not with me. He is at a respite centre a few miles away.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
