<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Compasion on Ghostdogs</title>
    <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/tags/compasion/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Compasion on Ghostdogs</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 13:35:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://ghostdogs.co.uk/tags/compasion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>You win or you learn</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/you-win-or-you-learn/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 13:35:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/you-win-or-you-learn/</guid>
      <description>Now just to get things straight I am not talking about a competetion in what follows. I am talking about supporting my son and part of that is understanding his complex behaviour and seeing things from his point of view.
You win or you learn is an important perspective for me. It reminds me that even when I come out of a situation with Tam I have to be positive and find the best way forward with that attitude.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Respite Part 2</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/respite-part-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2019 13:29:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/respite-part-2/</guid>
      <description>Dropping Tam off at the respite centre was hard, especially after being at the beach with him all day. The drop off was quick and consisted of a kiss and a bye-bye. I hoped that all of the preparation had worked. I have talked to Tam many times about him staying at the centre and having an adventure and sleep over. With his lack of verbal comebacks it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to totally understand how much he understands.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saying thank you is important</title>
      <link>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/saying-thank-you-is-important/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 14:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://ghostdogs.co.uk/blog/saying-thank-you-is-important/</guid>
      <description>During the time since Bev died a particular kind of music and a particular band have given both me and Tam a lot of solice. That band is Alterbridge. A rock band that I don&amp;rsquo;t like to put in a particular pigeon hole, they are Alterbridge.
Bev came to know Alterbridge through me and loved the vibe of the band and she loved the loud songs but also loved the quieter songs that they do.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>